Spencer Knight

■ email@spencerknightdev.com 480-228-2828 spencerknightdev.com github.com/maryPopplns

Summary

Highly motivated, self-taught web developer with 1.5 years of JavaScript experience creating user interfaces and API's. 5+ years in technical roles. Proven communication skills in fast paced environments as a technician and supervisor.

Skills: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Node, unit/integration testing, git, communication, problem solving, team player.

Professional Experience

07/2019 - 10/2020 Phoenix, AZ

Technical Support Specialist, *OpenTech Alliance*

- Remote troubleshooting of payment kiosks, access control systems, and various SASS products.
- Created documentation utilized by installers, customers, and technical support.

05/2014 - 05/2018 Norfolk, VA

Aviation Structural Mechanic, *US Navy*

- Manager (E-5): Oversaw 22 sailors in the rehabilitation of 314 pieces of battle control equipment at LIFAC facility, saving \$42,250 in rework costs.
- Technician (E-4): Performed rehab/troubleshooting on various aircraft components, resulting in a 98% sortie completion rate.

Projects

05/2022 - present

Chair Fit

- TypeScript, React, Node.
- Fitness/prehab application for those who sit all day.
- Currently in development.

04/2022 - 05/2022

Blog CMS

- React, React Testing Library, Jest.
- User interface for managing my portfolio's blog content. Implemented with textgears API to assist with spelling/grammar errors.
- Unit testing resulted in 95.5% line coverage.

03/2022 - 04/2022

Blog API

- Node, MongoDB, SuperTest, Jest.
- REST API for handling all CRUD operations of my blog posts. Implemented text2data API to analyze the sentiment of blog comments and remove negative ones.
- JSON web tokens for stateless sessions.
- Integration tests resulted in 99.4% line coverage.

Education

08/2010 - 05/2011 Scottsdale

Computer Science, Paradise Valley Community College